# **Dhaval S. Patel**

140 N Fiore Pkwy Email: dhaval96patel@gmail.com

Phone Number Vernon Hills, IL 60061 **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhaval96patel/ (224)-770-1491

## **SUMMARY**

I am a graduate student pursuing Masters in Data Science from Northwestern University while continuing work. Interested in transitioning to a Data Scientist role based on academic skills. Currently, Data Engineer with hands-on experience working with Cloud platforms, using Python. Involved in the creation of ETL pipeline scripts following ingestion, transformation, and extraction processes on data with Cloud technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL (NU)

Master Degree in Data Science

**GPA:** 4.0/4.0

University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL (UIC)

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Certification: Google Associate Cloud Engineer

Programming: Java, C++, JavaScript, ReactJS, SQL, Python, C, C#, .NET, Selenium, PySpark, AutoSys

IDE: PyCharm, Visual Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, Jenkins, MySQL Workbench, Google Cloud Cloud Services: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Publicis Sapient | Adobe Campaign Data Project (MGM Resorts) Data Engineer

Las Vegas, NV (Remote)

Anticipated: Jan 2024

**May 2019** 

**GPA:** 3.48/4.0

Oct 2020 – Present

- Developed Data Management ETL workflows used for targeting, segmenting, campaign execution, and performing A/B testing on offer engine to customers based on different marketing channels.
- Design, build, deploy, and monitor campaigns leveraging Adobe Campaign Standard Application. Developed Selenium Automation Selenium script in Java for Adobe Campaign to more efficiency on new features for MGM Resorts instead consuming time on manual tasks.

# Publicis Sapient | North America Distribution Marketing Project (Capital Group)

Irvine, CA (Remote)

Data Engineer

June 2020 – Sept 2020

- Utilized PySpark and Python script for reading parquet files to export data from SQL Data Warehouse to Azure Data Lake Store.
- Involved in converting SQL queries into Spark transformation using PySpark for partitioning data in the script. Developed standardized PowerShell and Jil scripts for batch process jobs using AutoSys scheduler.

# **Publicis Sapient | Subscription Business App Launch (Polaris)**

Chicago, IL

ASP .NET Developer

*Jan 2020 – May 2020* 

- Advanced development designing and building APIs, Micro Services using C# in TDD (Test Driven Development) methodology of different CRUD operations.
- Implement token-based authentication API to activate, create, and login account for the customer while using Polaris Subscription website and application.

### Publicis Sapient | Japan Data Analytics (McDonalds & Google)

Chicago, IL

Data Engineer

June 2019 – Jan 2020

- Develop Python scripts integrating Google Cloud Storage to extract Machine Learning output from BigQuery to the output bucket. Modify transformation ETL code to fix data quality wherever required by the data science team. Create Bash Scripts invocation in Python Scripts for data cleanups.
- Build ETL pipeline scripts using python apache beam Cloud Dataflow to transform data from Google Cloud Storage to BigQuery for inputs to machine learning models. Automation of ETL job to transfer inbound and outbound data between Microsoft Azure Blob storage and GCP Cloud Storage bucket.